# SAMANTHA PONCE

## **CONTACT**

Address: Brentwood NY 11717

Phone: 631-740-5034

Email: Samanthap once 5@gmail.com

https://samanthaponce.herokuapp.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/samantha-

ponce-0bb6ba1a9/

https://github.com/Samanthaponce5

### **SKILLS**

- Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, ReactJS, Redux, CSS, HTML, Restful API, PostgresSQL, GitHub
- Web-Based Software Engineering, Full-Stack, Frontend Web Development

#### **WORK HISTORY**

**Dental Assistant,** 08/2020 to Current

American Dental - Hicksville, NY

- Educate patients by giving oral hygiene, plaque control, and postoperative instructions.
- Prepared patient X-rays for review by the dentist.
- General chair-side duties to assist procedures, including general, endo, and oral surgery.

**Dental Assistant,** 10/2019 to 03/2020

Dental365 - Bellmore, NY

**Dental Assistant,** 01/2018 to 09/2019 **HRHCare** - Amityville, NY

**Dental Assistant,** 03/2017 to 10/2017 **Great Expression Dental Centers** - Bayshore, NY

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript-based programming with a background in Dental Assisting which has provided me with strong skills in problem-solving, decision-making, organization, listening, and working under pressure. Can quickly learn and master new technologies; successful working in both teams and self-directed settings. Skilled at contributing to design, development and implementation as conscientious, upbeat and knowledgeable team member.

## **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Certification: Web Development, 06/2020

Flatiron School - Manhattan, NY

**Associates**: Liberal Arts and Science, 06/2019 **Suffolk Community College** - Brentwood, NY

#### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Jack's Journey -

<u>Frontend</u> - https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/thePlasticJourney-frontend <u>Backend</u>-https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/plasticTalesBackend <u>Demo</u>-https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xkX2xINaMAQ

- An interactive educational site where users learn more about plastic pollution and the effects it has on the ocean.
- Built by using a ReactJS library, and a Rails-API backend using Postgres database.
- Implemented vanilla CSS for design

<u>Picology</u> - <u>Frontend</u>-https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/Ecomm-frontend <u>Backend</u>-https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/Ecomm-backend <u>Demo</u>-https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SsByJf9NJJ4&feature=youtu.be

- Picology is an e-commerce site where users can navigate through a gallery ranging from nature, aerial, and city photography and can choose to buy any of the photography listed and checkout to have it mailed to their homes.
- Developed using a ReactJS library and a Rails-API backend using Postgres database.
- Applied vanilla CSS for design

<u>Omega Sound</u> - <u>Frontend</u> - https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/music-app <u>Backend</u> - https://github.com/Samanthaponce5/music-app-mod3 <u>Demo</u> - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wdjvTJGPTFE&feature=youtu.be

- Omega Sound is designed to let users search and listen to any songs they would like.
- Created by using Vanilla Javascript and Rails-API backend
- Employed the Spotify API for music
- Design created with vanilla CSS